CHASE KING

Student at the University of Washington

I am a curious and self-motivated junior undergraduate studying computer science, applied mathematics, and computational neuroscience. My academic and research interests primarily revolve around artificial intelligence and machine learning, and using neuroscience principles from the human neocortex as a paradigm for designing intelligent machines.

TECHNOLOGIES

- ◆◆◆◆ → Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS
- ◆ ◆ ◆ ◆ ♦ Python, React, NodeJS, Git, LaTeX
- ◆ ◆ ◆ ♦ MongoDB, Redis, PHP

ACTIVITIES / ATHLETICS

Audi Cycling Team (Kryki Sports sponsored by Audi Bellevue)

Sep 2018 - Present

- Race in Pro/Category 1/Category 2
 USA Cycling races in the Pacific
 Northwest and on the West Coast.
- Connect and engage with teammates, many of whom work at local companies including Microsoft, Amazon, and T-Mobile.

Husky Cycling Club, Admin/Officer

- Lead weekly group rides students and help foster a community of cycling enthusiasts with diverse backgrounds and interests.
- Help organize UW collegiate race weekend (permits, travel, housing)
- Spring race weekends with other PNW universities.

Machines Who Learn Sep 2018 - Present

 UW reading group discussing ML and AI research papers.

CONTACT

- Web: <u>chaseking.me</u>
- Email: <u>chasek22@uw.edu</u>
- Github: <u>@chaseking</u>
- LinkedIn: <u>in/chase-king</u>
- Strava: <u>athletes/chaseking</u>

(References available upon request.)

EDUCATION

University of Washington

GPA: 3.92 / 4.0

Sep 2018 - Present Graduation expected June 2022

- B.S. CS (Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science & Engineering)
- B.S. ACMS (Applied & Computational Mathematical Sciences: Data Sciences & Statistics)
- Minor in Neural Computation and Engineering
- Relevant Coursework: Honors Advanced Calculus, Graduate Machine Learning, Graduate Computational Neuroscience, Graduate Algorithms, Probability, Optimization

WORK EXPERIENCE / PROJECTS

Beewriter — Full Stack Engineer

Jan 2020 - Present

- Deployed machine learning models and NLP techniques to detect grammar mistakes and provide further writing suggestions.
- Migrated backend to AWS Lambda, ensuring uptime and scalability.
- Implemented logging and tracking tools to monitor product usage and deployed an interactive dashboard to visualize various metrics.
- Redesigned website, making it responsive on mobile devices.

Marin Academy — Web Development Intern

2017 - 2018

- Wrote and designed a front- and backend responsive web application for a campus communication system known as the daily bulletin.
- Built a touchscreen kiosk application for student and guest usage.
- Rolled out custom digital signage across campus
- Tools and technologies used include: HTML/CSS, PHP, NodeJS, React, WordPress, Google APIs, Raspberry Pi.

Freelance Software Development

2012 - 2018

- Develop personalized web applications for clients.
- Utilized TensorFlow to train a model for detecting cheating players on Minecraft multiplayer game servers

HuddleMC, LLC — Co-Founder, Lead Developer

2014 - 2016

- Implemented backend architecture allowing for seamless cross-communication between multiple dedicated servers and dynamic node allocation (based on game demand).
- Developed a web panel for server status and management.
- Used profiling tools to develop highly-optimized Java code for multiplayer Minecraft servers, improving free memory by over 40%.
- Tools and technologies used include: Java, MongoDB, Redis, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Python.